financialexpress.net 2019-06-18

# Privacy and Cookies | FE Financial Express

This Privacy Policy was updated on 18th May, 2018

To see the Privacy & Cookie Policy for FE's suite of client portals, MI product and regulatory services please click here.

## **SUMMARY**

When you contact us via FinancialExpress.net we collect some personal information so that we can get back in contact with you. To improve the experience, we use services like Google Analytics, which collects anonymous browsing information such as the most viewed products and services on the website. We may occasionally use cookies to serve you relevant ads and appropriate content, and to remember your details to pre-populate your details in forms.

We’ll only send you email newsletters or marketing messages by email if you’ve asked for them or if they are necessary for us to fulfil our obligations to you (e.g. product updates for the products you have purchased from us) – and you can stop receiving them at any time. You can control cookies using your browser settings. If you have any questions about the data we have on you, including to verify it is accurate please contact us (details at the bottom of this page).

## **ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

Trusted by the thousands of investors, advisers, asset managers and platforms who use Financial Express (FE) data, software and investment advice every day, FE is the UK's leading investment ratings and research agency.

This Privacy Policy explains how FE uses information you provide to us or that we collect about you, how we collect it and which other trusted organisations we share it with. It also tells you how you can limit the information we collect and exercise your data rights.

**Also see:**

  * For more information about FE please visit our [website here](http://www.financialexpress.net/).

## **ABOUT US**

Financial Express (“FE”, “FinancialExpress.net”, “we”, “us”, “our”, “the website”) is part of Financial Express (Holdings) Limited. You can find our contact information [here](http://www.financialexpress.net/ "FE").

We may share the information we collect across our group companies and websites including but not limited to FE Investments Limited, FE Analytics, FE Trustnet and FE Investegate. 

## **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?**

### **1\. Information that relates directly to you such as your name and email address**

We collect information about you when you fill in a contact form on the site. When you submit a ‘contact us’ form, we ask you for your full name, business address, business telephone number, business email address and other personal information. Occasionally we may ask you for other details for the purpose explicitly stated on the form on the website.

If you complete a ‘contact us’ form via the website we may contact you by email, phone or post via your preferred contact method, where you have expressed a preference. You can change your communication preferences via the instructions that accompany each piece of communication (e.g. links to manage preferences in emails we send to you).

### **2\. Information that does not directly identify you such as your browsing behaviour on FE**

Through the use of cookies, we may collect data on the pages you’ve viewed, information about your computer, including where available your operating system, browser version, domain name and IP address and details of the website that you came from.

**FinancialExpress.net, and any other websites, products or services from FE are not intended to collect or process special types of data such as medical or biometric data, nor any data relating to children.**

## **HOW WE USE INFORMATION**  

### When you access the website we might store and use your information to:

  * Remember you when you visit our website and to see which product or service information pages and other pages you visit. We do this using cookies.
  * Identify your interests using anonymized data. We may use this to create audience segments that we then use to serve targeted, relevant advertising or content to you.
  * Identify aggregated and anonymised browsing behaviour on the website.
  * Target advertising to you based on your IP address.
  * To provide you with information by email, post or phone, about products or services that you request from us, such as email newsletters, marketing emails and special offers, tailored to your specific interests, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes and by such means. We may also pass your data to a select group of third parties whom we have appointed to carry this out on our behalf.
  * To ensure the content we display to you on the website is done in the most appropriate and efficient way, such as by identifying the device you are using and formatting the website appropriately.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts between you and us and/or in relation to our terms and conditions.
  * To enable you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

We may also send you emails to provide information and keep you up to date with developments on our website or regarding the products and services that you use. It is our policy to have instructions on how to unsubscribe so that you will not receive any future e-mails.

You agree that we may disclose to any regulatory authority to which we are subject and to any investment exchange on which we may deal or to its related clearing house (or to investigators, inspectors or agents appointed by them), or to any person empowered to require such information by or under any legal enactment, any information they may request or require relating to you, or if relevant, any of your clients.

### **HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION**

When you access or complete a contact form on the website, we collect information on you in the following ways:

  * directly from you – when you complete a contact form or any other form where we ask for personal or non-personal information.
  * indirectly from you via your browsing behaviour on the website using a variety of web technologies such as cookies and other digital tracking tools.
  * we may also use personal and/or non-personal information about you that we have collected on one of our other websites or from 3rd parties such as industry or regulatory database providers. This information may have been collected in-person, by telephone, on websites or in other ways.

### **YOUR PERMISSION TO BE CONTACTED**

We always endeavour to provide a substantial and meaningful explanation of the scope and the purpose for which we are collecting your information at the point at which it is collected, as well as providing you with the means to freely grant, or withdraw your consent for us to collect and store your information, and to use it to contact you where applicable.

Occasionally we may ask for your permission to share your information with 3rd parties we work with to offer you relevant information, products or services by email. This will be explained at the point at which your information and consent is collected, and your consent can be withdrawn at any time.

### **ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION AND CORRECTION**

We want to ensure that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date.

You can update your contact preferences using the **FE’s preference centre** on the website. Alternatively, to see what personal information we have collected from you, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, deactivate it by emailing [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

You have the right to access information held about you. If you wish to receive a copy of any personal information we hold, please email your request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0167646560756071736e75646275686e6f4167686f606f6268606d647971736472722f6f6475).

### **WHERE AND HOW WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) in order to facilitate our use of that information as stated above. It may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers ([FE’s Appointed Sub-processors](http://www.financialexpress.net/appointed-sub-processors)). Such staff may be engaged in, amongst other things, the provision of support services. We will take all steps reasonably necessary, including the use of encryption, to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy and the General Data Protection Regulations.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is never completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. You will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless we have been negligent or in wilful default.

Please refer to [FE’s Appointed Sub-processors](http://www.financialexpress.net/appointed-sub-processors).

### **How long do we keep your data?**

We will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### **COOKIES**

A cookie is a small file containing a piece of information (a string of letters and numbers that acts as an identifier) that is placed on your browser when you visit certain websites. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

### **Types of cookies we use:**

When you access our site, we ask for your consent to allow us to store the following cookies on your device.

**Essential cookies:** We use Google Tag Manager to manage many of our analytics and third-party cookies. We use CloudFlare for security and optimising the website’s performance – this requires CloudFlare to use cookies.

**Analytics cookies  **anonymously remember your computer when you visit the website. They keep track of, for example, the number of visitors who browse the website, their browsing patterns, which country they are in and what devices is used to visit the website. We might use that information to target advertisements to you on our and other websites.

**Advertising cookies** enable us to identify what types of adverts you have seen, for example so that you’re not shown the same advertisement too many times. We also use advertising cookies to help us use targeted advertising. We may use cookies set by other organisations so we can more accurately target advertising to you. These cookies are anonymous- they only collect information on what you have looked at on the website, not who you are. We may also set cookies on selected other sites that we advertise on in order to identify you (anonymously) as having visited those sites before or after you’ve visited the website so we can then target our advertising based on this information.

**Other third-party cookies:** Other organisations may also set their own cookies in order to anonymously track your engagement and interaction with their products and services on the website. An example of this could be if you were to ‘like’ a Research article using the Facebook Like button, Facebook may place a cookie on your browser to measure this. We cannot access these cookies (likewise, these organisations cannot access cookies we place on your browser).

### **When you access our site, we ask for your consent to allow us to store the following cookies on your device:**

### **Analytics Cookies**

  * Google Analytics
  * New Relic
  * Google Analytics Audiences
  * Permutive
  * Hubspot

### **Advertising cookies**

  * Doubleclick / Google Publisher Tag
  * Google Adsense
  * Google Pingback
  * Google Ad Measurement
  * Google Safeframe

### **Other third-party cookies**

  * Facebook
  * LinkedIn
  * Google+
  * Twitter

### **MANAGING COOKIES**

Most browsers allow you to block cookies, as well as deleting existing ones. To do this look at the “help” menu on your browser. Please note though, that if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or part of our site and you will still be shown advertisements, just less relevant ones. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our site. You can also delete cookies from your browser – use your browser’s ‘help’ section for specific instructions, or visit the ‘[ **Cookies and me’**](https://cookies.insites.com/disable-cookies/) website for user-friendly instructions for most popular browsers.

The main advertising serving system we use is DoubleClick by Google. To see what information Google collects and how you can manage it please visit  <https://privacy.google.com/intl/en/your-data.html>[](https://privacy.google.com/intl/en/your-data.html)

### **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### **OTHER WEBSITES**

Our site contains links to other websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### **CONTACT**

If you want more information or have any questions or comments relating to our privacy policy please contact FE’s Data Protection Officer:

Address: Data Protection Officer, FAO Sorin Pop, 3rd Floor, Hollywood House, Church Street East, Woking, Surrey, GU21 6HJ, United Kingdom

Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#81e7e4e5e0f5e0f1f3eef5e4e2f5e8eeefc1e7e8efe0efe2e8e0ede4f9f1f3e4f2f2afefe4f5)

Telephone: 01483-783940
